A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Records of the Special Committee for Program Policy Review in the 1960s FA708
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Appendix A
  - Proceedings, Sessions I & II, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 March 2 (Report 11152)
  - Proceedings, Sessions III & IV, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 March 3 (Report 11153)
  - Proceedings, Sessions V & VI, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 March 16 (Report 11154)
  - Proceedings, Sessions VII & VIII, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 March 17 (Report 11155)
  - Proceedings, Sessions IX & X, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 April 13 (Report 11156)
  - Proceedings, Sessions XI & XII, Special Committee on Program Review, 1962 April 14 (Report 11157)
  - Directives and Terms of Reference for the 1960s, 1962 June (Report 2795)
  - First Interim Report, Ad Hoc Committee on Special Programs, Waldemar A. Nielsen, 1959 June 15 (Report 10556)
  - Program Submission Concerning Future Program Activities, The Ford Foundation Special Committee, 1962 Spring (Report 11158)
  - The Ford Foundation in the 1960s, Statement of the Board of Trustees on Policies, Programs, and Operations (also a Foundation publication), 1962 July (Report 11159)
  - The Role of the Foundation in American Society. W. McNeil Lowry, Director, Program in Humanities and the Arts, The Ford Foundation, The Nassau Club, Princeton, 1958 April 16 (Report 11160)
  - Address by John J. McCloy, United States Military Academy, West Point, New York, 1961 December 6 (Report 11161)
  - The Road to Peace, An Address by John J. McCloy, Counsel, Milbank, Tweed, Hope & Hadley, New York, 1961 November 29 (Report 11162)
  - Follow-Up of a Special Committee Report, 1962 (Report 12674)
  - Policy, Program, and Operational Directives for the 1960s (draft ofthe "Directives..."), 1962 May (Report 2855)
- Appendix B
  Appendix B
  The following lists the table of contents for the "Directives and Terms of Reference for the 1960s" and the "Supporting Materials," Volumes I - IV.
  DIRECTIVES AND TERMS OF REFERENCE FOR THE 1960S Introduction Part I Policy Directives Program Directives Operational Directives Part II "Terms of Reference" - Introduction Educational Affairs The Arts and Sciences Public and Economic Affairs International Affairs Overseas Development
  FORD FOUNDATION PROGRAM EVALUATION, 1951-61, SUPPORTING MATERIALS, VOLUME I A. Education Program, 1951-61 Main Paper: Overall Review Special Program in Education Educational Television Supplementary Paper: Education Program, 1954-56 B. International Training and Research Program, 1951-61 C. Humanities Program, 1956-61 D. Arts Program, 1957-61 E. Science and Engineering Program, 1957-61 F. Behavioral Sciences Program, 1951-57 G. Public Affairs Program, 1950-61 Main Paper: Review of Early Years, 1950-57 Urban and Regional Affairs Youth Development Law and the Administration of Justice The Public Service Supplementary Papers: The Fund for the Republic Television-Radio Workshop H. Economic Development and Administration, 1951-61 Regular Program Advancement of Business Education Population Problems Problems of the Aging I. International Affairs Program, 1951-61 J. Overseas Development Program, 1951-61 South and Southeast Asia Near East and Africa Latin America and the Caribbean K. Appendix Summary Table for Total Grant, Project, and Other Data, 1951-61 Yearly Distribution of Grants by Purpose within Programs through 1961
  TRUSTEE AND STAFF PROPOSALS FOR FORD FOUNDATION PROGRAMS FOR THE 1960S, SUPPORTING MATERIALS, VOLUME II Part One: Trustee Proposals for Future Program Part Two: Staff Proposals for Future Program A. Educational Affairs B. Arts and Sciences C. Public and Economic Affairs D. International Affairs E. Overseas Development Part Three: Proposals Submitted by Individual Officers and Program Directors on Aspects of the Foundation's Over-all Program
  CONVERSATIONS AND CORRESPONDENCE WITH AMERICAN AND INTERNATIONAL LEADERS AND EXPERTS, SUPPORTING MATERIALS, VOLUME III Part One: Partial List of Persons Outside the Foundation from Whom Ideas Were Received Part Two: Synthesis of Outside Conversations and Submissions Part Three: Selected Letters, Memoranda, and Papers Submitted by Outside Leaders and Experts Part Four: Informal Notes on Study Director's Outside Interviews Part Five: Summaries of Special Committee Luncheon and Dinner Discussions with Outside Leaders
  SPECIAL PAPERS AND WORKING DOCUMENTS, SUPPORTING MATERIALS, VOLUME IV The Continuing Role of the University Public Relations and the Office of Reports Dissemination and Accessibility of Grant-Supported Reports and Findings Foundation Commitments, Fiscal Years 1962-1966 Sample Policy Paper Regarding a Trustee Fund for Local Charitable Purposes Study Director's "Check List" of Problems and Issues Special Committee Agenda Chronological Summary of Special Committee Proceedings Bibliography of Documents Available in the Special Committee Files